

Matthew Montoya

Full Stack Web Developer



Summary



I am a full-stack developer with a background in retail management. I am passionate about meeting clients' needs, solving problems, and working with CSS! Based on my past experience, I look forward to working with teams to build interactive and responsive applications!



Experience

2018-03 -2018-06

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly

Completed a 12- week, 600+ hour Web Development Immersive program in which I developed and deployed three full-stack applications while using the industry's best practices. Two of the projects were done independently and one was developed in a team environment.

Full-stack projects include:

JamMate

- JamMate is a full stack application created with the intention of allowing authenticated users to connect with local artists based on the type of instrument(s) they play and their music genre.
- This project was developed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and Handlebars for the front-end client. The back-end was constructed using Ruby on Rails.

Sserpdrow

- Team project in association with Patrick O'Day and Sparrow Rubin.
- We developed a full-stack application that would allow authenticated users to create web pages and blog posts.
- This application was developed using Express.js, Mongoose, and MongoDB to construct an API.

Pro[Stock] Systems

- Pro[Stock] Systems is a full-stack application developed with the intention of allowing authenticated users to be able to keep track of their personal inventory.
- As inventory levels change, the user will be able to updated or delete inventory based on their needs.
- This project was developed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and Handlebars for the front-end client. The back-end was constructed using Ruby on Rails.

2014-07 -**Assistant Manager** 2018-03

Tumi

- Hired, trained, coached, and developed a strong team.
- Monitored, maintained, and verified inventory accuracy and product levels.
- Managed shipments and ensured timely delivery.
- Strived to drive sales to meet monthly and yearly goals.
- Audited daily receipts and bank deposits.
- Created monthly schedules and audited payroll.

Education

2018-03 -2018-06

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive

2012 -

2014

University of Massachusetts Boston

Iberian and Latin American Studies



Phone

(978) 930.3721

Address

Greater Boston Area

E-mail

mattrmontoya@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/mattrmontoya

GitHub

github.com/Matty-Montoya

Porfolio

mmontoya.me



HTML

Bootstrap

CSS / SASS

Javascript

Node.js

Ember.js

JQuery Ruby

Ruby on Rails

MongoDB

Mongoose

Handlebars

PostgreSQL

Git/Github

Atom Editor

Sublime Editor



Native Spanish